we are asked to use the hash
select method to iterate over the
numbers hash
and return a hash containing only the
key value pairs
where the value is less than 25
we're going to assign the returned hash
to a variable
and print its value we'll name this
variable
low numbers
and we know just from the problem
description that we need to call the
hash select method
on our numbers hash
as we iterate through the numbers hash
the select method will pass
each key value pair to the block
the key will be assigned to the first
block parameter which we'll call
key and the value assigned to the second
block parameter
which we'll call value
now we need to think about what we want
to do within our block
in order to return a hash that includes
only the key value pairs
with a value less than 25 the new hash
returned by the hash select method will
include
only the key value pairs for which the
return value of the block
evaluates as true we can compare
our value to 25
if the value is less than 25
the return value of our block will be
true if the value is
greater than or equal to 25 our block
will return false
and the key value pair of our current
iteration will not be included in the
new hash
so let's output our new hash low numbers
and we expect our output to match the
expected output
which is to include only the key low and
its value
10.
and that's what we see
you